根据人人影视字幕修正时间轴错误
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
时间轴   想念Gallifrey的Wholock       今       永远的永远
后期         吉吉       翻|校|监          草草
摩斯探长前传
第四季  第二集
圣歌
咪咪
乔伊·佩蒂博说出真理
保持英国得体
《贾丝汀  美德的不幸》
乔伊·佩蒂博说出真理
《男孩女孩出来玩》
野林乐团
乔·佩蒂博太太
年鉴秀
精彩时代  迷幻药的政治
野林乐团
人物聚焦  克里斯托弗·克拉克
《贾丝汀  美德的不幸》
《男孩女孩出来玩》
《詹妮弗有时》
《贾丝汀  美德的不幸》
蝴蝶蜕变  心思改变
《詹妮弗有时》
野林乐团解散  青少年心碎
恋人
*我的眼泪如夏季的疾风骤雨  亲爱的*
*Like summer tempests came my tears, love*
*当我得知了你的欺骗*
*When I learned you'd been untrue*
*但雨后必然有彩虹*
*But after rain must come a rainbow*
*所以彩虹出现之前  我要这么办*
*So until then here's what I do...*
*骗自己你爱我  亲爱的*
*Make believe you love me, darling*
*骗自己你在乎我*
*Make believe you care*
*骗自己你需要我*
*Make believe you need me*
*骗自己你就在我身边*
*And I'll make believe you're there.*
*带着耶稣的十字架*
*With the cross of Jesus*
*继续向前进*
*Going on before'.*
我们在天上的父  愿人都尊你的名为圣
Our Father, who art in heaven, hallowed be Thy name.
愿你的国降临
Thy kingdom come,
愿你的旨意行在...
Thy will be done...
*我们会说"我愿意"*
*And we'll say I do...*
*尽管天空阴沉灰暗  亲爱的*
*Though the skies are dark and grey, love*
*但天气预报员说没关系*
*And the weatherman says fine*
*在我心里*
*And in my heart...*
"我扑倒在祈祷椅前
"I cast myself down upon the prie-dieu,
大声向天父敞开心扉
"And while aloud I open my heart to the Eternal,
罗兰的残忍行为进一步加剧了"
"Roland in a still crueler manner intensifies.
*骗自己你爱我  亲爱的*
*Make believe you love me, darling*
*骗自己你在乎我*
*Make believe you care*
*骗自己你需要我*
*Make believe you need me*
*骗自己你就在我身边*
*And I'll make believe you're there*
*骗自己我尚未心碎*
*Make believe my heart's not broken*
*骗自己那是真的*
*Make believe it's true...*
我们要乔伊
We want Joy'.
我无比荣幸地向大家介绍
It gives me great pleasure to introduce to you
一位信仰坚决
a woman strong in faith,
决心坚定的女士
steadfast in her convictions.
女士们先生们  朋友们
Ladies and gentlemen, friends,
有请乔伊·佩蒂博太太
please welcome Mrs. Joy Pettybon'.
*就让雨水掩藏我的眼泪*
*So let the raindrops hide my teardrops...*
上周三晚
Last Wednesday evening,
我们看了一个节目
we saw a program,
那真是我看过的最龌龊的节目
and it was the dirtiest program I've ever seen.
我们反对英国广播公司
We object to the disbelief, the doubt
通过电视和无线电  向千万家庭
and the dirt that the BBC pours into millions of homes
灌输的质疑  怀疑和污秽
through the television screen and through the wireless'.
*骗自己我尚未心碎*
*Make believe my heart's not broken*
*骗自己那是真的*
*Make believe it's true*
*骗自己你终有一日会爱我*
*Make believe you'll love me one day*
*我们会说"我愿意"*
*And will say I do...*
*骗自己你爱我  亲爱的*
*Make believe you love me, darling*
*骗自己你在乎我*
*Make believe you care*
*骗自己你需要我*
*Make believe you need me*
*骗自己你就在我身边*
*And I'll make believe you're there*
*骗自己我尚未心碎*
*Make believe my heart's not broken...*
*骗自己那是真的*
*Make believe it's true.*
*骗自己你终有一日会爱我*
*Make believe you'll love me one day*
*我们会说"我愿意"*
*And will say I do*
停  停止录音
Cut'. Cut'. Stop playback'.
老天爷
Oh, for goodness' sake...
他是我的人  继续吧
He's with me. Carry on.
好  谢谢
Right, thank you.
可以清场吗
Can you clear the set, please?
没事  你没疯
Don't worry, you haven't gone mad.
他们在拍电视节目
They're filming a television show.
咪咪
Mimi.
《吻我》
"Kiss Me."
什么
What?
她去年的金曲
Her big hit from last year.
控制室说是毒品案
Operations Room said drugs.
昨天的带妆彩排后
Porter found a bag of pot
门房在高级研究员公共休息室里
in the senior common room yesterday,
发现了一包大麻
after the dress rehearsal.
而之前只有野林乐团进去过
The only people who have been in there are The Wildwood,
咪咪的特邀嘉宾
Mimi's special guests.
你可能听说过他们
You might have heard of them.
没有吗  好吧
No, well.
上个月  他们的主唱在
Last month their singer stole a car
哈登姆路的红狮酒吧外偷了辆车
from outside The Red Lion on the Haddenham Road.
案件被撤销了
Case dismissed.
据说他的经纪人收买了车主
Word is his manager paid off the owner of the car.
好吧
Right.
经纪人是谁
So who's the manager?
拉弗·斯潘德  认识你很高兴
Ralph Spender. Pleased to meet you.
我想告诉你
Now, I just want you to know
我跟你们一样  对此事很重视
I take this as seriously as you do,
但相信我
but believe me,
这绝非事实
there is not one iota of truth in it.
野林乐团都是干净的好男孩
The Wildwood are nice, clean boys.
任何姑娘都会乐意带回去见家长的那种
The sort any girl'd be happy to bring home to meet her parents.
我父母不会乐意我带个偷车贼回家的
I don't think my parents would like me to bring home a car thief.
那完全是场误会
That was a complete misunderstanding.
地方法官也这么认为
The magistrates agreed.
相信我  他们是干净的好男孩
I'm telling you, they're good, clean boys,
他们的形象也干干净净
with a good, clean image.
-不管怎样  -朗姆酒可乐
- Well, nevertheless... - The odd rum and coke.
野林乐团偶尔会喝点
That's The Wildwood drink, yes.
但毒品
But drugs?
不会的
No.
那你认为那大麻是怎么来的
So, how do you explain the marijuana?
我不知道
I can't.
或许是粉丝的
Well, fans maybe?
媒体没事找事
The press trying to make a story?
或是节目组的其他人
Some of these other types from the show.
做电视的人
Television people.
你也知道他们什么样
You know what they're like.
"如果你来牛津  你会死的"
"If you come to Oxford, you will die."
我昨天收到的  高级警司
I received it yesterday, Chief Superintendent.
我收到的一些信  你都难以想象
You wouldn't believe some of my correspondence.
我还会收到下流照片
I get dirty pictures.
狗屎
Dog mess.
什么都有
All sorts.
是真的
She does.
人们的行为真是野蛮
People carrying on like animals.
是啊
Quite. Quite.
但之前没有这种事  没有直接威胁
But nothing like this before, no direct threat.
总有些人
Well, there are always people
怨恨那些为主行事的人
who resent those going about Our Lord's work.
但你想不到哪个特定的人吗  佩蒂博太太
But nobody specific comes to the mind, Mrs. Pettybon?
有很多人寄过
Well, a lot of people send
很多不好的东西来  督察
a lot of very unpleasant things, Inspector.
如果我们个个当真
If we took them all seriously...?
你的安全当然是我们的头等要务
Your safety is our paramount concern, of course.
瑟斯戴
Thursday?
请放心  佩蒂博太太
Rest assured, Mrs. Pettybon,
我们会派最好的警官负责此事
we'll put our best man on it.
我给你介绍下团员们
Let me just introduce the boys.
吉他手  肯·威尔丁
Ken Wilding on guitar,
他弟弟尼克  主唱
and Nick, his brother, lead vocals.
贝斯手  克里斯
Chris on the bass
鼓手  我们的狂野小子
and our resident madcap on the drums.
斯蒂克斯·诺博
Stix Noble.
怎么回事
So what's happening, then?
少校说你们是警察
The Major says you're the police.
昨天你们离开公共休息室后
A bag of pot and some marijuana cigarettes
那里发现了一袋大麻和一些大麻烟卷
were found in the common room yesterday after you left.
怎么回事
What is this,
陷害我们吗
some sort of frame-up?
得了  肯  别惹人厌
Come on, Ken. Don't be a drag.
不  让我来处理  尼克
No, I'm dealing with this, Nick.
如果不是陷害  那算什么
So, if it's not a frame-up, what is it?
敲诈吗
A shakedown, is that it?
肯  他没那个意思
Ken, he doesn't mean that.
给他钱就好了  拉弗
Just pay the man, Ralph.
谈论贿赂警察
Threatening to bribe a police officer
可是严重罪行  威尔丁先生
is a serious offense, Mr. Wilding.
我没有
I didn't.
我叫他给你钱
I told him to pay you.
失陪了  我们还要再拍一条
Now if you'll excuse us, we've got another take to shoot.
不行
No.
我或许无法证实大麻是你们的
I may not be able to connect you to this pot,
但这算是非正式警告了
but consider this an informal caution.
你们所有人
All of you.
非正式
Informal.
谢谢
Thank you.
这样  我给你们送点宣传材料过去
Listen, let me send you some promotional material.
你们可以拍卖掉
You can auction them.
给警察遗属基金会
For the police widows and orphans.
就当是我的感谢
As a token of my appreciation,
以表示大家还是一团和气
just to show there's no hard feelings.
他们的最新唱片  海报
The boys' latest LP, some glossies.
当然了  都是签名的
All signed, naturally.
你们可以留下来  看完表演
Feel free to stick around, watch the rest of the show.
我还有更值得做的事呢
I've got better things to do with my time.
什么事
Such as?
我要拿她怎么办
What am I meant to do with her?
就盯着她点就好
Just keep an eye, that's all.
她也就在这里待一晚
She's only in town overnight.
她正在进行全国巡回演讲
Part of this nationwide speaking tour she's on.
教堂  市政厅什么的
Church halls, town halls.
她在收集签名  是吧
She's collecting signatures, isn't she?
对  是份请愿  她打算交到
Yeah, some petition she means to hand in
唐宁街首相那里
to the prime minister at Downing Street.
你怎么看
What do you make of it?
亨利的邮戳
Henley postmark.
四天前寄的
Sent four days ago.
我可以查查字体
I can look into the typeface.
到现在已经有不知多少人的手碰过了
Well, I doubt we'll have much luck after all the hands
所以希望不大  但还是查查指纹吧
it's been through, but best get it fingerprinted.
你在学院那边怎么样
How did you get on at the college?
无法证明他们跟大麻有关
Oh, there was nothing to tie them to the pot,
我只能给他们经纪人下达了非正式警告
so I gave their manager an informal caution
就算完事了
and left it at that.
真不懂他们为何喜欢这玩意
I don't know why they bother with the stuff.
我就没感觉
Never did anything for me.
你抽过大麻
You've smoked pot?
什么时候
When?
在沙漠里
Up the desert.
在那里叫麻醉品
They call it kif out there.
有些小伙子都抽上瘾了
Some of the lads were silly with it.
你试过吗
You ever tried it?
我可是现役警察
I'm a serving police officer.
再说  我喜欢保持头脑清醒
Besides, I like to keep a clear head.
你喝的啤酒可不少
Put enough beer away.
啤酒是健脑食物
Beer's brain food.
长官
Sir.
巡警叫我们去处理一具在王冠酒馆后
Uniform's asking us to attend a body found
发现的尸体
behind The Crown Pub.
似乎是他杀
Looks like foul play.
约一小时前  店主发现了尸体
Body was found about an hour ago by the landlord.
没有钱包  或其他身份证明
No wallet or other means of identification.
也不是常客
He isn't a regular,
昨晚没去酒吧
and wasn't in the bar last night.
店主最后检查院子是什么时候
What time did the landlord last check the yard?
大概昨晚9点
About 9:00 yesterday evening.
天还没黑
Still light.
如果他当时就在  那应该能看到
If he was here, he would've seen him.
有位邻居说
One of the neighbors said
她凌晨3点听到了车声
she heard a car about 3:00 in the morning.
除此之外  没什么不寻常的了
Apart from that, nothing out of the ordinary.
医生
Doctor.
督察
Inspector.
成年男性
Adult male.
20到25
Early to mid-20s.
昨晚8点到12点间死亡
Died sometime between 8:00 and midnight last night.
被用绳子勒死
Strangled with a ligature.
大概有我手指粗的绳子
About the thickness of my finger.
或许是吊窗绳
Sash-cord, perhaps?
我没动他  但看死后尸僵
He's as I found him, but postmortem lividity
他是趴着死的
says he died on his front.
注意他躯干侧面的印记
Note the marks on the side of his torso.
他被移过尸
He's been moved.
在他死后一两小时内
Within an hour or two of his decease.
进行详细验尸后
Be able to give you furthers and betters
会有更多信息
once I've opened him up.
昨晚有失踪案上报吗
Any missing persons in overnight?
没有  长官
No, sir.
是体力工吗
Manual laborer, maybe?
因为他的鞋吗
State of his boots, you mean?
鞋底有水泥或混凝土
Cement or concrete in the tread.
我叫巡警去本地各建筑工地问问
I'll get uniform to put the word out to local building sites.
看有谁没去上班
Anybody that's not turned in.
我知道
I know, I know.
真恶心
It's disgusting.
佩蒂博太太马上就好
Mrs. Pettybon won't be a moment.
《每日邮报》
The Daily Mail.
我们数了  14个"该死"  6个"他妈的"
We counted 14 "bloodys," six "bleedings"...
还有什么  贝蒂娜
What else, Bettina?
还有两个"混蛋"和一个"王八蛋"
Two "bleeders" and a "bastard."
两个"混蛋"和一个"王八蛋"
Two bleeders and a bastard.
在警局这就是寻常的一晚
Sounds like a regular evening down the nick.
这可是家庭节目
And this is a family program.
我很期待读到你的文章
Well, I shall be very interested to read your article.
上帝保佑你
God bless.
好啊
Well.
这就是你最好的警官吗
This is your best man, is it?
摩斯警员
Detective Constable Morse.
乔伊·佩蒂博太太
Mrs. Joy Pettybon.
寡妇
Widow.
格莱特利牧师你已经见过  督察
Reverend Golightly you know, Inspector.
这是我女儿  贝蒂娜
May I introduce my daughter, Bettina?
我给你戴上这个吧
And may I give you one of these to wear?
这是不行的  太太
I wouldn't be allowed, Madam.
作为警察  我必须保持中立
As a police officer I have to remain impartial.
但没人能反对这种观点吧
But no one could argue with the sentiment, surely?
显然还是有人反对的
Someone could, plainly.
佩戴它可能会被视为拉帮结派
Wearing that could be seen to betoken an affiliation,
佩蒂博太太
Mrs. Pettybon,
而我们执行公务
and we have to go about our business
必须绝对公平公正
without fear or favor to any.
但你们不执勤时没关系吧
But when you're not on duty?
警察时刻都职责在肩  牧师
A police officer's always on duty, Reverend.
就像您自己
Much like yourself.
我需要一份您的行程
I'll need a copy of your itinerary
您在牛津期间的
while you're in Oxford.
我们主要都在这里
Well, we'll be here, mostly.
乔伊今晚要上电视节目《年鉴》
Joy will be appearing on the Almanac TV program this evening.
在阿斯顿的西耶拉电视演播室录制
It's being filmed at Sierra Television Studios in Aston.
在伯明翰吗
In Birmingham?
抱歉  那里不在我们辖区之内
Oh, I'm sorry, I'm afraid that's beyond our jurisdiction.
警察局长向我保证了
I was assured by the Chief Constable
你会全力配合
of your full co-operation.
摩斯警员会全程陪同
Detective Constable Morse will be on hand throughout
以确保不会发生不妥之事
to ensure nothing untoward befalls.
你可以信任他
You can rely on him.
你觉得佩蒂博太太的事是怎么回事
What is it, do you think, with Mrs. Pettybon?
她显然很会
Well, she's clearly got a talent
惹人生气
for rubbing people up the wrong way.
你真要我去做保姆吗
Look, do you really want me on babysitting duty?
我们在酒馆院子里发现的尸体怎么办
What about this body that we found in the pub yard?
史蒂夫·卡特先生  长官
Mr. Steve Carter, sir.
来报案说他的工人今早没来上班
Come in to report his laborer not turned up for work this morning.
特征描述与酒馆尸体吻合
Description matches our body behind the pub.
我说了
It's like I told him,
他没去上班
he didn't turn in for work.
我是砖瓦匠
I'm a brickie.
你搭档不来  你就干不了活儿
Your mate don't show up, you're in lumber.
所以我给他老太打了电话
So, I give his old woman a ring.
他妈妈
His mum, like.
问他去哪了
To see where he'd been.
她说巴里根本没回家
Well, she said that Barry never come home.
他叫巴里·芬奇  是吗
And it's Barry Finch, you said?
雀那个芬奇
Like the bird. Yeah.
你最后见他是昨天晚上
You last saw him yesterday evening.
对
Yeah.
我大概5点收工
I knocked off about 5:00.
5点
5:00.
本想送他回家
Was gonna give him a lift back.
但他决定再留会儿
But he decided to stay on for a bit.
游个泳
Have a swim.
游泳
A swim?
你们是在哪工作
Where were you working, then?
枫芯堂
Maplewick Hall.
班伯里附近一栋挺大的房子
Big old place out by Banbury.
巴里一半时候干活儿都心不在焉
Barry couldn't keep his mind on the job half the time.
就因为那里有一堆女人
What with all the birds and that they've got up there
穿得挺凉快还到处晃
wandering around in their altogether.
怎么说
How's that?
那里现在住了群流行明星
Bunch of pop stars up there at the minute.
野林乐团
The Wildwood.
他和卡特先生之间一切都好吧
Everything was all right between him and Mr. Carter, was it?
史蒂夫吗
Steve?
是的  他对巴里很好
Yes, he's been very good to Barry.
能去枫芯堂工作  他一定很开心
Must have been delighted to be working at the Maplewick Hall.
他正好是他们的大歌迷
Being such a fan of the group.
是啊  他可开心了
Yes. He was made up.
他喜欢好多这种乐团
I mean he, he likes a lot of these groups.
但野林乐团一向是他最喜欢的
But The Wildwood was always his favorite.
你能想到任何会想害他的人吗
Can you think of anyone who would wish him any ill?
没有
No.
没有人会说他一句坏话
No one had a bad word to say about him.
他愿意帮助任何人
He'd do anything for anyone.
怎么会...
Why would any...
你们要找到伤害他的人
You find who hurt him.
你们要找到伤害我孩子的人
You find who hurt my baby.
我们会的  芬奇太太
We will, Mrs. Finch.
我保证
That's a promise.
加拿大很大  路易
Canada's a big territory, Louis.
我得挂了
Listen, I've gotta go.
尽快把数据拿给我
Get me those percentages as soon as you can.
瑟斯戴督察
Detective Inspector Thursday.
-拉弗·斯潘德  长官  -督察
- Ralph Spender, sir. - Inspector?
拜托  我们不都解决了吗
Come on, I thought we'd sorted all that out.
这是关于另一件事
This is about another matter.
我们发现了一具尸体  先生
There's a body been found, sir,
在城里一家酒馆的院子里
back of a pub yard in town.
是个小伙子  巴里·芬奇
A young man called Barry Finch.
他近来在这里做工
He's been working here as a laborer,
跟一个叫卡特的砖瓦匠一起
with a bricklayer name of Carter.
对
Yeah.
那个巴里啊
Yeah, that Barry.
很不错的小伙子
Very nice young man.
请坐
Please.
你们来根雪茄吗
Can I offer you a cigar?
不了  谢谢  先生
I won't, thank you, sir.
我们已知他最后被见到
The last sighting we have of him alive
是昨晚  在这里
is here last night.
他留下游泳了
He was staying on for a swim.
我当时在伦敦
Well, I was in London.
我在那里有个办事处
I've... I have an office there.
芒特街
Mount Street.
有人可以证实吗
Anyone confirm that?
我母亲
My mother.
菲莉丝
Phyllis.
布鲁诺  我的司机
Bruno, my driver,
他大概7点把我送回了家
he dropped me home about 7:00.
我整晚上大部分时候都在跟同事们通电话
I spent most of the evening on the telephone to colleagues
先是跟纽约的  然后跟加州的
in New York, and later California.
我策划让乐团下个月去那里进行大巡演
I'm planning a big tour for the boys there next month.
跟奇想乐团一起
With The Kinks.
到"眼睛"  你把音降到G
On "eyes," you walk it down to a G.
-*眼睛...*  -对
- *Eyes...* - Right, so...
-*你*  -A  G小调
- *You...* - A, G sharp...
不不
Oh no, no, no.
G小调好难听
G sharp sounds horrible.
不  没事
No, that's good, cos...
尼克
Nick?
尼克  你能不能先别弹了
Nick, can you just leave off a minute?
我想试试我的新曲子
I wanna try my new one.
非常珍贵的哥特插图手稿
内容是各个时刻根据教义应念的祈祷
不会又是《珍贵时刻》里的典雅爱情故事吧
Not more tales of courtly love from Très Riches Heures?
《我的好凯特》可登上了榜单前五
"My Sweet Lady Kate" was top five.
是啊  我们就像群拉皮条的
Yeah, we looked like a bunch of ponces.
到底是什么呢
Yeah, so, what is it, then?
法国诗人
是改编自我读的一首波德莱尔的诗
Based on this poem I've been reading by Baudelaire.
不
Oh, no'.
不会又是那种儿歌吧
Not more nursery rhyme stuff?
-是新材料  -可并不新鲜了
- It's something new'. - It's not though, is it?
怎么不唱...
Whatever happened to...
*我今早醒来*
*I woke up this morning*
肯是对的
Ken's right.
那不是摇滚
It's not rock and roll, man.
你可能已经忘记了自己的出身  伙计
Yeah, you might've forgotten where you come from, mate,
但我们可没忘
but the rest of us haven't.
心离不开西伦敦的男孩吗
Take the boy out of the Goldhawk Road?
对  没错
Yeah, that's right.
好了  他不是那意思
All right, he didn't mean it.
美国蓝调布鲁斯乐手
你留着你的波德莱尔  我听我的博·迪德利
You keep your Baudelaire, and I'll stick to Bo Diddley.
好吗
All right?
我出去抽根烟
I'm going outside for a fag.
克里斯
Chris?
嗯
Yeah?
-你跟他说  -好
- Sort him out. - Yeah, I will.
告诉他我很抱歉
Tell him I'm sorry.
那该你去说  不是我
You should tell him then, not me.
小伙子们
Boys.
这两位先生有话找你们说
These gentlemen just want a word.
是吗
Oh yeah?
我们这次又干什么了
What're we supposed to have done this time?
是砖瓦匠的工人  巴里
It's the brickie's boy-- Barry.
他死了
He's dead.
死了
Dead?
怎么回事
How, what happened?
出事故了吗
He have an accident, or something?
他应该是被人杀了
It appears he was murdered.
卡特先生说  巴里下班后没走
Mr. Carter said that Barry stayed on after work
留下游泳了  是这样吗
for a swim, is that right?
对
Yeah.
谁叫他留下的
Who asked him to stay?
没谁
Nobody.
他什么时候走的
What time did he leave?
他在这里待到了8点
He was here till about 8:00.
差不多是7:45
It was about quarter to.
小姐是...
And you are, Miss?
皮帕·雷顿
Pippa. Leyton.
这些女孩是作为裁缝
The girls help out as seamstresses
帮团员们缝舞台服装
with the boys' stage clothes.
是这样吗
Is that right?
你多大了
How old are you?
18岁
Eighteen.
到下个生日时
Next birthday.
你呢  小姐
And you, Miss?
艾玛·卡尔
Emma Carr.
我们没做错什么
We're not doing anything wrong.
当然了
Course you're not.
这是自由国家
It's a free country.
有人看到芬奇先生离开时去哪了吗
Did anybody see which way Mr. Finch went when he left?
他说要搭车回城的  是吧
He said he was going to hitch a lift back into town, didn't he?
你不是说你当时在伦敦吗
I thought you said you were in London?
是的  好像是肯告诉我的
Yes, I think Ken told me.
是吧  肯
Didn't you, Ken?
对
Yeah.
没错
That's right.
他如果留得晚  一般就这么做
That's what he usually did if he stayed on late.
还有两个成员  是吧
There's two more, aren't there?
他怎么了
What happened to him?
巴里
Barry?
我们就是来调查这个的  先生
That's what we're here to find out, sir.
是个事故还是怎么
I mean, was there an accident, or what?
看来不是  你是...
It would appear not, Mister...?
抱歉
Oh, sorry.
克里斯托弗·克拉克
Christopher Clark.
斯蒂克斯
Stix.
鼓手
The drummer.
安娜-布丽特  克里斯的...
Anna-Britt, Chris's...
克里斯的妻子
Chris's wife,
但不知为何我们不能告诉别人
only for some reason we're not allowed to tell anyone.
只是生意
It's just business.
歌迷不希望知道他们已经结婚了
The fans don't want to know the boys are married.
你不是给了巴里份工作吗
You offered Barry a job,
是吧  拉弗
didn't you, Ralph?
我...
Well...
没有
No.
没有吗
No?
他似乎是这么认为的
He seemed to think you had.
我是说  如果有机会的话
I'd said, if something came up.
做司机或...
Driving or...
并没说定
It wasn't a firm offer.
他就是有点追星昏头了
He was a bit star-struck, that's all.
他和他的同事之间没什么问题吧
And was everything all right between him and his colleague?
跟卡特先生
Mr. Carter?
就我们所知是没有
As far as we know.
我们跟他们其实没多少瓜葛
Look, we really didn't have much to do with either of them.
巴克希医生
Dr. Bakshi,
他负责照顾团员们
he looks after the boys.
是吗  怎么说
Oh, yes, in what way?
他们是警察
These gentlemen are with the police.
有一位工人
One of the laborers has,
死了
...has died.
这样啊
I see.
回答你们的问题
In answer to your question,
我负责团员们的健康
I tend to the group's well-being--
身体  心理和精神健康
physical, mental and spiritual.
事实上  我跟尼克还约了4点的看诊
As a matter of fact, I have a 4:00 session with Nick,
为他今晚的电视表演做准备
to prepare him for tonight's TV performance.
除非你们有什么意见
Unless you've any objection.
没问题  先生
Very well, sir.
你觉得他走出这里了吗
You think he left here?
你觉得呢
Do you?
他们绝对有问题
They're a rum lot, and no mistake,
那经纪人也是
and I wouldn't trust that manager
完全不可信
so far as I could throw him.
好了
Now.
真有趣
Here's fun.
去世的巴里·芬奇
The late Barry Finch.
给明星打工的砖瓦匠小工
Brickie's laborer to the stars.
死因
Cause of death.
勒死
The strangulation?
他是被勒过
He was strangled, yes.
好几次呢
Several times.
但那并非死因
Only that's not what killed him.
不是窒息
It wasn't asphyxia.
而是心脏衰竭
His heart gave out.
勒颈是死亡过程中发生的
The strangulation occurred peri-mortem.
就在死亡时刻前后
On or about the moment of death.
但他本就要死了
He was already dying.
但不会是勒颈导致了他心肌梗塞吗
But couldn't the strangulation have caused the heart seizure?
是可能
Certainly.
当颈部迷走神经突然被施压
When sudden pressure is put on the vagus nerve in the neck,
确实可能造成立即死亡
instantaneous death can happen.
但你瞧  如果我...
But you see if I...
这样  你首先会怎么做
Now... what's the first thing you're going to do?
努力把它弄掉
I'm trying to get it off.
努力  没错
Ah try, yes.
在这样的情况下  按说该有擦伤
Now a case like this, one would expect to find abrasions--
脖子上应该有抓痕
scratches to the neck--
被害人手指甲里应该有他们自己的皮肉
the victim's own skin and flesh under their fingernails.
但芬奇先生没有
And that's not the case with Mr. Finch?
对
No.
你可以...
Would you...
当然
Oh, yes. Of course.
如果是因为他的手不能动呢
What if his hands weren't free?
并无迹象表明他被绑着
There's nothing to suggest he was bound.
手腕处无磨伤
No chafing to the wrists;
没有淤青表明他遭到了捆绑
no bruises to say he was restrained.
这没道理
It doesn't make sense.
为何要去勒死濒死的人
Why strangle a dying man?
幸好  那是你得琢磨的事
Well, that's your department, thankfully.
我更关心的是  什么东西能让一个健康的
I'm more concerned as to what would stop the heart
24岁男人的心脏停跳
of an otherwise fit 24-year-old.
他的东西在旁边那里
His bits and bobs on the side there.
没什么值得注意的
There's nothing remarkable.
如果不是他杀  为什么会有人想装成他杀
Why would someone want to make it look like murder if it wasn't?
都说不通  是吧
Nothing really adds up, does it?
你在跟踪我们吗
You following us?
不是
No.
我是跟佩蒂博太太来的
I'm here with Mrs. Pettybon.
那个老疯婆子
That batty old woman?
该有人教训她
Someone wants to put her straight.
是有人威胁这么做
Someone's threatened to.
威胁做什么
Threatened to what?
干掉她吗
Do her in?
老天爷  有点过了吧
Blimey, that's a bit much.
她虽然疯疯癫癫
I mean she's mad as a march hare,
但也没人希望她出事
but you wouldn't want anything to happen to her.
蠢婆娘
The silly cow.
喜欢这披风吗
Like the clobber?
所有人都穿这个
Everyone's wearing '.
那么
So'.
谢谢大家  晚上好
Thank you and good evening.
欢迎收看《年鉴》
Welcome to Almanac.
半小时的音乐  闲聊和时事
Half an hour of music, chat and current affairs.
我们今晚的节目相当精彩
And what a show we have for you tonight.
稍后  我们将独家专访
Coming up later, we have an exclusive interview
野林乐团的尼克·威尔丁
with Nick Wilding, of The Wildwood.
冷静  姑娘们
Steady, girls.
他的乐团将表演他们的最新曲目
And his group will be performing their latest sound
《詹妮弗有时》
"Jennifer Sometimes."
他的乐团
His group.
好啊
Nice.
他的乐团
His group.
但首先  我要对话
But before that, I'm going to be talking to
全国电视整顿协会的领袖
the leader of the National Clean Up Television Society,
保持英国得体活动的标志人物
figurehead of the Keep Britain Decent campaign
也是英国道德的守护者
and Guardian of the Nation's Morals.
女士们先生们  有请乔伊·佩蒂博太太
Ladies and gentlemen, Mrs. Joy Pettybon'.
谢谢你请我上节目  卡林德先生
Thank you for having me on your program, Mr. Calendar.
不客气
Not at all.
请叫我"朱利安"
And, "Julian," please.
佩蒂博太太
Now, Mrs. Pettybon,
据我所知  您正在进行自己的征程[十字军]
I understand you're on something of a crusade at the moment?
我不会用这样的字眼
I wouldn't put it in those terms,
但  是的  我想我们是在为主行事
but, yes, I suppose what we're doing is the Lord's work.
您在全国上下巡回
You're traveling up and down the country
为一份请愿收集签名  是吗
collecting signatures for a petition, is that right?
是的
We are.
这份请愿的内容是什么
And what's it calling for-- this petition?
其中就包括  让电视和无线电
Well, amongst other things, decency on television,
保持得体
and on the wireless.
我正打算上无线电呢  或者说电台
I was going to come on to the wireless, or the radio,
我们现在都这么叫了
as we tend to call it nowadays.
因为你所声讨的人之一
Because one of the people you've been complaining about--
事实上  你还呼吁
in fact, you've actually called for
电台禁播他的专辑
his record to be banned from the airwaves--
他今晚也在演播室
is in the studio with us tonight.
是吗
Is that right?
是的  当然  我说的就是
That is right, yes-- it is, of course,
流行乐团  野林乐团的尼克·威尔丁
Nick Wilding, of the pop group The Wildwood.
-抬脚  -那么
- Feet up. - Now
你究竟不喜欢他的音乐哪点
what is it you don't like about his music?
并不是音乐的问题
It's not the music, is it?
当然了  那是很吵
Of course it's too loud...
但我反对的是歌词
...but it's the words that I object to.
歌词
The words.
歌词有什么不对
What's wrong with them?
如果非要我明说
Well, if-if you want me to spell it out,
他们现在的这张专辑  是关于性的
this record they have at the minute, it's about S-E-X,
是吧  还有吸毒
isn't it, and drug taking.
好吧
All right, well,
那你稍后可以自己对他提出这些指控
you can put those charges to him yourself in a moment,
但首先  我们听听吧
but first, let's get an earful.
听听这争论的焦点
Hear what all the fuss is about.
有请他们  女士们先生们
Here they are, ladies and gentlemen.
把女儿锁好了
Lock up your daughters'.
野林乐团带来了他们的新歌《詹妮弗有时》
It's The Wildwood with their new sound, "Jennifer Sometimes."
*詹妮弗有时  坐在太阳下*
*Jennifer sometimes, sits in the sunshine*
*摆弄她的头发*
*Playing with her hair*
*回到旧学校  看一颗毒蘑菇下面*
*Go back to the old school, look under a toadstool*
*那里并没人*
*Hey, it's nobody there*
*詹妮弗有时*
*Jennifer sometimes*
让让啊
Mind?
你什么时候还看起《年鉴》了
Since when have you watched Almanac?
是工作
It's work.
什么工作
What work?
佩蒂博太太
Mrs. Pettybon.
摩斯在保卫她
Morse is on duty with her.
有人威胁她
There've been threats.
我可不意外
I'm not surprised.
对别人的行为指手画脚
Telling people what they should and shouldn't.
"得体"
"Decency."
要我说  她就是喜欢听自己夸夸其谈
She just likes the sound of her own voice, if you ask me.
他们不就是琼喜欢的那个吗
Aren't those the ones that Joan likes?
野林乐团
The Wildwood.
我可不知道
I wouldn't know.
你当然知道
You would.
你去沃尔沃斯替她买了他们的第一张专辑
You fetched their first record for her from Woolworths.
你说是就是吧
If you say so.
怎么  我们都不能提她了吗
What? We're not allowed to talk about her now?
弗莱德
Fred?
有什么好谈的
What's there to talk about?
那不是你的真心话
You don't mean that.
如果她想打电话  早就打了
If she was going to call, she'd have called.
还好吗
All right?
嗯  我...
Yes, I...
妈妈抛头露面时我会紧张
I get nervous when Mummy makes an appearance.
我必须出来喘口气
I have to step out.
这是我的恶习
It's my vice.
恶心的习惯
Filthy habit.
你不必担心
You mustn't worry.
这世上好多疯子呢
The world's full of cranks.
你可能觉得妈妈也有点疯吧
You probably think Mummy's a bit of a crank.
我相信她是...真心的
I'm sure she's... sincere.
是的
She is.
她做了多久...
How long she been...
大概四年了
About four years.
但她是在爸爸过世后才真正投入进来的
But she really got into it after Daddy passed away.
他是个好人
He was a wonderful man.
是吗
Was he?
我们还是回去吧
We should probably go back inside.
是啊
Yes.
你不会告诉她吧
You, you won't tell her?
烟的事
About the cigarette.
不不
No, no, no, no, no.
谢谢
Thank you.
这些迹象都表明
These are symptoms of a...
社会缺乏信仰  自甘堕落
of a godless and degenerate society.
上周有个节目
There was this program last week,
简直是我看过的最龌龊的节目
and it was the dirtiest program I have ever seen.
-龌龊[脏]  -确实
- Dirty? - Well, it was.
什么意思
What do you mean?
他们是没洗澡还是怎么
The people in it hadn't had a wash, or what?
你很清楚我什么意思
You know very well what I mean.
我不清楚
I don't.
真的
Honestly.
什么叫"龌龊"
What's "dirty"?
龌龊就是龌龊  就是这样
Dirty's dirty. That's what dirty is.
是啊  但你觉得龌龊的
Yeah, but what's dirty to you
别人或许觉得能接受  是吧
might be quite acceptable to somebody else, mightn't it?
甚至很正常
Quite normal, in fact.
这个才不正常
This wasn't normal.
让我感到反胃
It made me physically sick.
究竟有什么不对
What was wrong with it, then?
是关于两个所谓的同性恋
It was about two of these so-called homosexuals.
什么叫"所谓"
How do you mean "so-called"?
《圣经》里可不是这么说他们的
Well, the Good Book's got quite a different name for them.
是吗
Has it?
那是怎么说的
Well, what's that, then?
鸡奸者
Sodomites.
不论我往哪看
Everywhere I look,
都躲不过这些污秽
I'm having it rammed down my throat.
我可不想它出现在我家客厅
Well, I don't want it in my lounge.
纵容社会
The Permissive Society.
是啊
Yes'.
就是这么说的
That's what they call it.
可没人问我容不容许
Well, nobody asked my permission.
好  说得对
Bravo'. Well said'.
胡说
Rubbish'.
好了  先生
All right, sir.
纯粹胡说
Absolute rubbish'.
不是胡说
It's not rubbish.
抱歉  谁让你说了算了
Sorry. Who put you in charge?
你图个什么
Where do you get off
非要教育我们该看什么
telling us what we can
该听什么
or can't see or hear?
艺术表达的自由呢
What about freedom of artistic expression?
别碰我
Don't-- do not touch me'.
Don't touch me'.
我这就走
I'm leaving.
我走
好啊
Well,
瞧瞧  女士们先生们
there we are, ladies and gentlemen.
直播放送的欢乐和刺激
All the fun and excitement of live broadcasting.
从不会无聊
Never a dull moment.
那么我们还是回到这个问题上来
If we might return now to the matter at hand,
佩蒂博太太  你之前说起龌龊...
Mrs. Pettybon, you were talking about what's dirty...
你找我吗
You wanted to see me?
对
Oh, yeah.
今早有个男人送到前台的
A bloke dropped it off at the front desk this morning.
警长  这个工人的事有进展吗
Oh, Sergeant, any developments on this laborer?
-巴里·芬奇  长官  -是的
- Barry Finch, Sir. - Just so.
我稍后要去见助理警察局长
I'm seeing the Assistant Chief Constable later.
他肯定会问起
He's bound to ask.
没什么可查的  长官
Not been much to go on, sir.
他此前品性优良
A person of previous good character,
曾是圣玛丽的唱诗班成员  直到变声
choirboy at St. Mary's, till his voice broke.
据我们所知没有敌人  没有犯罪记录
No enemies that we know of, no criminal record.
他尸体上的印痕呢
What about this mark on his body?
我也在琢磨呢  长官
Just trying to figure that out myself, sir.
X标记点
X marks the spot.
好了  够了
All right'. All right'. That's enough'.
你也想找打吗
Want some too, do you?
我是警察
I'm a police officer'.
我的警察证  识字吗
My warrant card-- if you can read.
我们这是为了孩子
It's the kiddies we're thinking of.
他就是个变态
He's a bloody pervert.
给我走
On your way, go on.
走吧
Come on.
来
起来
Let's get you...
来
Come on.
你没事吧
You all right?
没事吧
You okay?
你说呢
Do I look it?'
那女人是个禽兽
The woman's a monster'.
她害我被起诉
She had me prosecuted, didn't she?
怎么说  你是...
How's that, mister...?
杰赛普
Jessop.
达德利·杰赛普
Dudley Jessop.
我经营...
I run...
我曾经营一本杂志
I ran a magazine.
《精彩时代》
The Exciting Times.
佩蒂博太太不喜欢
Mrs. Pettybon took exception
我们的"男学生"特刊
against our "schoolboys" edition
想告我亵渎上帝
and tried to do me for blasphemy.
我写了篇文章
Oh, I wrote an article
把耶稣和圣彼得写成了情人
that considered Jesus and St. Peter as lovers.
我能理解这可能会让她不高兴
I can see how that might rub her up the wrong way.
那是关于爱的
It was about love.
她管那叫"龌龊"
She said it was "dirty."
爱怎么会是龌龊的
How can love be dirty?
如果不龌龊  你大概是没做对
Well, if it isn't, I expect you're not doing it right.
刚刚还挺顺利
I thought that went well.
除了那一点的不愉快
Apart from that little bit of unpleasantness.
如果能安慰你  你的一些支持者
Well, if it's any consolation, some of your supporters
把他打了个半死
have just beaten the living daylights out of him.
你错了
You're mistaken.
我亲眼所见  佩蒂博太太
I saw it, Mrs. Pettybon.
但你的表现太棒了
But you did ever so well.
是吧  牧师
Didn't she, Reverend?
当然
Oh, yes.
非常棒
Yes, marvelously well.
祝福者送来的
Well-wishers.
花和...应该是巧克力
Flowers and chocolates, I believe.
都先拿回酒店去吧  莫温
Just take it all back to the hotel for now, Mervyn.
我们早上把它们送给患病有需要的人
We'll dispense them to the sick and needy in the morning.
那我...
Well, I'll...
你肯定累了
You must be tired.
那我道晚安了
I'll say good night.
晚安  莫温
Good night, Mervyn.
如果没别的事
If there's nothing else.
你今天帮了大忙  警员
You saved, Constable.
恐怕是没干什么有用的事
More squandered, I'm afraid.
外面会有巡警站岗
There'll be a uniform officer outside,
您应该可以安睡
should help you to sleep safely
不必再担心什么了
without any further worries to trouble you.
摩斯先生
Mr. Morse?
我...
I...
不知能不能请你
I... I don't suppose I could ask you
替我开窗
to open my window for me,
可以吗
could I?
不知为何卡住了
It... it sticks somewhat,
昨晚好热
and it was so hot last night.
没问题
Yes.
谢谢
Thank you.
就是有点僵
Just a little stiff, that's all.
你想来杯酒吗
Would... would you care for a drink?
今天挺累的了
Oh, it's been quite a long day.
当然了
Of course.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
不不
No, no, I...
喝一杯应该也没什么的
I'm sure one drink wouldn't do any harm.
但已经过12点了
Though it has gone 12:00.
酒吧肯定早关门了
I doubt the bar will still be open.
我有一瓶酒
I... I've got a bottle.
如果你不介意伏特加
If you don't mind vodka.
玻璃水瓶旁边有个水杯
And there's a glass for water by the carafe.
我可以拿浴室的漱口杯
And I can get a tooth glass from the bathroom.
那会有薄荷味吧
Won't that be a bit minty?
我不介意
Oh, I don't mind minty.
*詹妮弗有时  坐在太阳下*
*Jennifer Sometimes, sits in the sunshine*
*摆弄她的头发*
*Playing with her hair*
*回到旧学校*
*Back in the old school*
*看一颗毒蘑菇下面*
*Look under a toadstool*
*那里并没人*
*There's nobody there.*
谢谢你
Thank you.
照顾妈妈
For looking after Mummy.
不客气
Not a problem.
这样的案子  小心胜过后悔
Cases like this, I think it's better to be safe than sorry.
我不知道她会怎么说我
I don't know what she'd say at me
在房间里招待陌生男人
having a strange man in my room.
我可不想给你惹麻烦
I'd hate to be the cause of any difficulty.
事实上  我还是走吧
In fact, I should probably go.
再喝一杯吧
Have another.
拜托
Please.
我没怎么有机会跟人说话
I don't get to speak to many people
平时只有妈妈和格莱特利牧师
besides Mummy and Reverend Golightly.
我耽搁你去见谁了吗
Am I keeping you from someone?
-你妻子...  -没有
- Your, your wife... - No.
-或未婚妻  -没有
- Or fiancée... - No.
我公寓里等着我的只有瓦格纳
The only thing I have waiting for me at my flat is Wagner.
那好悲哀
Well, that's sad.
还有更糟的事呢
There are worse things.
有吗
Are there?
我想不到
I can't think of any.
我清楚孤独的滋味
I know what it's like to be lonely.
我不孤独
I'm not.
没特别孤独
Particularly.
是吗
Really?
你看上去很孤独
You seem lonely.
上帝饶恕我
God forgive me.
可怜的格莱特利牧师
Poor Reverend Golightly.
他特别喜欢甜食
He had such a sweet tooth.
但我从没觉得这有什么
Didn't seem any harm in it.
他一向那么帮忙
He was always so helpful.
我不想为此小题大做
I just didn't like to make a fuss.
是否有办法查明  巧克力是谁送的
Is there any way to find out who donated the chocolates?
人们会把这些礼物留在舞台
People just leave them on the stage
或送去我化妆间
or send them to my dressing room.
我们并不做记录
We don't keep a register.
你觉得...
What, you think...
那是给妈妈的吗
You think they were meant for Mummy?
很可能  小姐
It's possible, miss.
昨晚在《年鉴》节目上
There was a disturbance
发生了一点小骚动
at the Almanac program last night.
因为一个叫达德利·杰赛普的人
A man called Dudley Jessop.
他是个堕落之人
He's a degenerate.
你企图让他以亵渎上帝罪被起诉  是吗
You tried to have him prosecuted for blasphemy, is that right?
总得有人为主说话
Someone had to stand up for Our Lord.
(sniffles)
(music continues)
没发生什么
Nothing happened.
他离开了
He left.
他离开了  然后死了
He left, and he died.
(music continues)
(gate creaking)
? Jennifer sometimes,
sits in the sunshine ?
(knock at door)
? Back in the old school,
look under a toad stool ?
? There's nobody there ?
对不起
I'm sorry.
真对不起
I'm so sorry.
你不该来这里
You shouldn't be here.
我必须见你
I had to see you.
进来吧
Come in.
谢谢
Thank you.
? Jennifer sometimes ?
不听瓦格纳吗
What happened to Wagner?
是为了工作
It's for work.
抱歉  你有酒吗
I'm sorry, do you have anything to drink?
? Jennifer sometimes ?
(record stops)
妈妈发现我拿了两个杯子
Mummy found I had two glasses out.
她
She...
她逼我告诉她  你进过我的房间
She forced me to tell her you'd been in my room.
你惹麻烦了吗
Are you in trouble?
妈妈
...Mummy.
还有这一切
And all of it.
(dog barking outside)
我爱你
I love you.
这就是我来说的
That's what I really came to say is...
我爱你
I love you.
佩蒂博小姐
Miss Pettybon...
叫我贝蒂娜
Bettina.
天啊  你有别人了  是吗
Oh God, there's someone else, isn't there?
(sniffles)
(birds chirping)
"我扑倒在祈祷椅前
"I cast myself down upon the prie-dieu,
大声向天父敞开心扉
"And while aloud I open my heart to the Eternal,
罗兰的残忍行为进一步加剧了
"Roland in a still crueler manner intensifies...
我把后面暴露给他
"Upon the hindquarters I expose to him,
任他发泄恼火和折磨"
his vexations and his torments.""
又见了
Hello again..
一切都好吗
Everything all right?
还以为你不会再来找我们了
I'd thought you were done with us.
还没完事呢
No, not quite.
我在找斯潘德先生
I'm actually looking for Mr. Spender
和其他团员
and the rest of the group.
去伦敦了
Gone to London.
拍照
For a photo-session.
之后好像还有电台节目
I think some radio thing later.
但尼克在
Nick's here, though.
他怎么没跟其他团员一起走
Why didn't he go with the rest of the group?
他好像不想去
Don't think he felt up to it.
他在哪
Well, where will I find him?
秘密
It's a secret.
在他的冥思地
In his thinking spot.
他会去那里创作歌曲
He goes there to work on songs.
我真的想找他谈谈
Well, I really would like to talk to him.
麻烦你告诉我那是在哪
If you could tell me where that is.
你找不到的
You won't find it.
为什么
Why not?
因为那是个魔法之地
Because it's an enchanted place.
如果你想我可以带你去
I can show you if you like.
你说你跟乐团在一起几个月了
So you said you've been with the group for a couple of months.
-是吗  -是乐队
- Is that right? - Band.
尼克更喜欢叫"乐队"不是"乐团"
Nick prefers "band" to "group."
是吗
Does he?
你怎么会跟他在一起的
How was it you came to be with them?
就是那样
Just did.
皮帕和我在他们的一场音乐会后去了后台
Pippa and me went backstage after a concert they did
跟他们聊了起来
and got talking to them.
然后就留下了
And just... stayed on, I suppose.
你喜欢吗
Do you like it?
真是精彩纷呈
Oh, it's a scene.
我能告诉你件事吗
Shall I tell you something?
你想就说吧
If you like.
《詹妮弗有时》那首歌
You know "Jennifer Sometimes."
那是讲我的
That's about me.
尼克为我写的
Nick wrote it about me.
还用了我的名字
He put my name in it.
你不是叫艾玛吗
I thought your name was Emma.
是的
It is.
艾玛·詹妮弗·达布利·卡尔
Emma Jennifer d'Arblay Carr.
但他只用了詹妮弗
But he just used the Jennifer bit.
到了
There you are.
在那里
It's over there.
你不来吗
You're not coming with?
不  那是他的魔法之地
No, it's his enchanted place.
我们不能去
We're not allowed.
再见
Bye.
你想要点酒吗
Would you like some wine?
不了  谢谢
No. Thank you.
"人该始终沉醉"
"One should always be drunk."
《Get Drunk》查尔斯·波德莱尔
我觉得还挺有道理  是吧
I think there's something in that, don't you?
可能吧
Possibly.
这就是你的魔法之地吗
So this is your enchanted place, is it?
是的
That's right.
巴里·芬奇来过这里吗
Did Barry Finch ever come here?
没有
No.
你怎么看他
What did you make of him?
我不想谈
I don't want to talk about it.
不管怎样  查清他的死是我的责任
Nevertheless, it's my job to find out how he died.
我搞不懂你
I can't figure you out.
有什么需要搞懂的
What's to figure?
我就是个警察
I'm just a policeman.
对  但你知道现在在发生着什么事  是吧
Yeah, but you know there's something happening, right?
在这里
Here.
在全世界  每个地方
In the world. Everywhere.
我们的同龄人  在寻找答案
People our age. Looking for answers.
但你穿着正装
But you are in a suit.
我喜欢穿正装
I'm happy in a suit.
你难道不想拓展思维吗
Don't you want to expand your mind?
你读赫胥黎吗
You read Huxley?
我想看看那门后有什么
I want to see what's beyond the door.
《知觉之门》
赫胥黎在嗑药后  将体验写成的著作
有其他东西
There's something else.
你只需要找对钥匙
You just gotta find the right key.
-毒品吗  -没什么太狠的
- Drugs? - Nothing heavy.
冥想
Meditation.
致幻蘑菇
Mushrooms.
我和克里斯以前放学后会去找致幻蘑菇
Me and Chris used to go looking for mushrooms after school.
你试过吗
You ever tried 'em?
只吃过英式早餐里的那种
Only as part of an English breakfast.
你想找到什么呢
So what do you expect to find?
在门后
Beyond the door?
无限
The infinite.
无限可能
Infinite possibility.
无限的爱
Infinite love.
我们都是坠落的天使
We're all just angels that fell from grace.
每个人都是
Every one of us.
没有羞耻
There is no shame.
没有罪过
No guilt.
每个人都在以
Everyone vibrating
跟宇宙一样的频率震动
at the same frequency as the universe.
如果你跟巴里·芬奇发生了什么
If something happened with Barry Finch...?
没发生什么
Nothing happened.
他离开了
He left.
他离开了  然后死了
He left, and he died.
他们带走了他
They took him.
谁
Who?
神
The Gods.
鉴证科完成了佩蒂博太太收到的信的检验  长官
Forensics have come back on that letter Mrs. Pettybon got, sir.
所有指纹均属于佩蒂博太太
No prints beside Mrs. Pettybon's,
她女儿和格莱特利牧师
her daughter's and the Reverend Golightly's.
还有你  布莱特先生和摩斯
Oh, and yours, Mr. Bright's and Morse's.
那肯定是戴了手套  那个寄信的人
Must have worn gloves, then. Whoever sent it?
看来是的
Looks like it.
那信封呢
What about the envelope?
长官
Sir?
他们查信封了吗
Did they check the envelope?
上面肯定有一堆指纹
Well, it'll be covered in prints.
经过了邮政总局嘛
Been through the GPO--
收信员  分拣员  邮递员
the collector, the sorter, the postman.
肯定都拿过
They'll have had their dabs all over it.
但不会摸到内侧
Not inside, they won't.
内侧
Inside.
警长
And Sergeant.
还有件事
One more thing.
克拉克太太
Mrs. Clark?
我这就走了
I'll be on my way now.
其实  我真有件事想找你
Actually, I did want to see you about something.
您能穿件衣服吗
Would you put something on, please?
裸体让你不舒服吗
Does nakedness make you uncomfortable?
喝酒吗
Drink?
不了  谢谢  克拉克太太
No, thank you, Mrs. Clark.
你不能喊我安娜-布丽特吗
Can't you call me Anna-Britt?
我们最好正式一点
I think it's better we keep it formal.
英国人
English.
好拘谨
So uptight.
你有什么事想找我
What was it you wanted to see me about?
那个男孩
That boy.
-建筑工  -是
- The builder. - Oh, yes.
他怎么了
What about him?
摩斯
Morse?
你好  伙计  怎么回事
Hello, matey? What's this?
警局说你在这里
The station said I'd find you here.
我刚从枫芯堂来
I've just come from Maplewick Hall...
摩斯  你好
Morse. Hello.
你好大胆
You've a nerve'.
他来干什么
What's he doing here?
摩斯警员是为其他事来的
Detective Constable Morse is here on other business,
佩蒂博太太
Mrs. Pettybon.
我告诉警察局长我不希望他参与此案了
I told the Chief Constable I don't want him involved.
你没听到吗
Perhaps you didn't hear.
我是为其他事来找瑟斯戴督察
I'm seeing Inspector Thursday about another matter.
好了  伙计
All right, matey.
我能想象是什么事
And I can imagine what.
回你房间去  贝蒂娜
Go to your room, Bettina.
-妈妈  -回你房间去
- Mummy... - Go to your room'.
那好
So?
希望你是来告诉我你们已经逮捕他了
I hope you've come to tell me you've arrested him?
-逮捕谁  佩蒂博太太  -达德利·杰赛普
- Arrested who, Mrs. Pettybon? - Dudley Jessop.
他在我主眼中有违人伦
He's an abomination in the eyes of our Lord.
奇怪  警察训练手册里
Strangely enough the police training manual
没提过有违人伦什么的
omits to mention abominations.
是啊  幸好  瑟斯戴督察和我
Yes, well, thankfully, Inspector Thursday and I
还记得人们曾经体面得体的时代
can remember a time when people were decent.
其实  佩蒂博太太
Actually, Mrs. Pettybon,
我是来找你谈你的那封信
I'm here to talk about this letter of yours.
威胁你生命的那封
The one threatening your life.
怎么了
Oh, yes?
斯特兰奇
Strange?
我们检验过了
We had it examined.
查指纹
For fingerprints.
我们在上面发现了你的
We found yours on there,
你女儿的  还有格莱特利牧师的
and your daughter's, and the Reverend Golightly.
当然了
You would.
我给他们看过
I showed it to them.
我们还在信封内部发现了
We also found a partial print of your second,
你食指  中指和无名指的部分指纹
third and fourth finger on the inside of the envelope.
还有密封的边沿上
On the sealed flap.
那是我拆信时沾上的
Yes, well, I would have done that taking the letter out.
不太可能
Unlikely.
大部分人拿信时
You see, most of us remove a letter
都是指甲对着信封内侧
with our fingernails facing inside the envelope.
像这样
Like so.
是不太可能  但不是全无可能
Well, it's unlikely, but it isn't impossible.
我拿过它很多次
I handled it a lot.
这我也考虑过
Yes, I thought about that.
但有一个地方  你是不可能
However, there is one place where it would have been impossible
留下拇指指纹的
for you to leave your thumbprint.
邮票下面
Under the stamp.
我们非常小心才提取到
We had to lift it off very carefully,
但邮票上有一小块
but there's one small part of that stamp
胶水没粘牢
where the adhesive didn't quite take.
在那里  我们找到了清晰的部分指纹
And that's where we found a good partial print
是你右拇指的
of your right thumb.
那是不可能的
You see, that would be impossible.
你的指纹怎么会
How could your fingerprint
在一个陌生人寄给你的信的
be underneath a stamp on a letter sent to you
邮票下面
by a complete stranger?
我告诉你我怎么想吧
I'll tell you what I think, shall I?
我想  那信是你自己寄给自己的
I think you posted that letter to yourself
目的是为自己博取同情
in an effort to gain sympathy for your cause
好获得更多影响力
and drum up trade.
你无法证明
You can't prove that.
我们能的  如果我们真努努力
Oh, I expect we can, if we really put our mind to it.
是这样吗
So let me get this straight.
克里斯托弗·克拉克的妻子
Christopher Clark's wife
听到有车离开枫芯堂
heard a car pulling out of Maplewick
当时是巴里·芬奇死的那晚的凌晨时分
in the early hours on the night Barry Finch died.
不是有邻居听到
There was a neighbor heard a car
有车停在过酒馆院子外吗
outside the pub yard, wasn't there?
或许是斯潘德把他的尸体丢在了那里
Maybe it was Spender dumped his body there.
斯潘德先生说他当时在伦敦  是吧
Mr. Spender said he was in London, didn't he?
他在芒特街的公寓
His flat in Mount Street.
跟美国人通话  你问过他了吗
Talking to America. You press him on that?
没  他跟尼克之外的其他乐队成员
No, he's with the rest of the band-- apart from Nick--
去做什么录音了
at some recording session.
你觉得他说的是实话吗
Think he's on the level?
尼克吗
Nick?
我觉得他  艾玛
I think there's something going on
和皮帕之间有什么
between him, Emma and Pippa.
他在隐瞒什么事
He's hiding something.
摩斯
Morse.
尼克
Nick'.
Nick?'.
尼克
Nick'.
-尼克  -尼克
- Nick'. - Nick'.
尼克
Nick'.
拜托  你在哪呢
Come on, where are you?'.
尼克
Nick'.
-尼克  -尼克
- Nick'. - Nick'.
尼克
Nick'.
给  警长的命令
Here we go, lads, Sarge's orders.
谢谢
Thanks...
他之前就在这里
This is where he was earlier.
发现什么了吗
Anything?
没有
No.
那是什么
The hell's that?
那边有什么
Somewhere over there.
那里
There.
他在那里
There he is.
尼克
Nick'.
-尼克  -尼克
- Nick'. - Nick'.
尼克
Nick'.
Nick,
-尼克  -尼克  是我
- Nick. - Nick, it's me.
-尼克  伙计  -尼克哥们
- Nick, mate. - Nicky-boy?
-是我们  没事的  -你怎么了
- It's us. It's all right. - What's up, man?
退后一点  退后
Stand back a little. Stand back. Stand back.
尼克  伙计  他怎么不说话
Nick, mate, why is he not saying anything?
给他点地方
Just give him some space.
你把他怎么了
What've you done to him?
好了
There we go.
没事了
It's all right, now.
我就照照你的眼睛
I'm just going to shine a little light into your eyes.
不会疼的
It's not going to hurt.
他是怎么了
What's the bloody matter with him?
他是我弟弟  你想想办法
Well, look, he's my brother, do something'.
看着我
Look at me.
他就是嗑嗨了而已
He's high, man. He's just high.
你冷静点  他没事
You need to stay cool. He's okay.
他只是嗑药了  他会清醒过来的
He's just on a trip and he's gonna come back down.
那可不是致幻蘑菇
That's not mushrooms.
他不会嗑别的
He wouldn't do anything else.
他不会嗑那些化学品
He wouldn't do any chemicals.
你们哪个混蛋给他下药了
I mean which one of you bastards dosed him?'.
他现在最需要的  是平静的环境
The main thing he needs is a calm environment,
一间安静较黑的房间  还得有人陪着他
a quiet and darkened room, and someone to stay with him.
我陪着他
I'll stay with him.
不  我陪着他
No. I'll do it.
-肯  -你做得够多了
- Ken'. - You've done enough, all right?
我走时他还好好的  我回来时他就...
I left and he was fine, and I come back he's...
他就疯疯癫癫的了
he's gone half out of his mind.
你们俩都离远点
So just stay away, the pair of you.
我又没做什么
I didn't do anything'.
我们会确保他得到妥善照顾的  肯
We'll make sure he's looked after, Ken.
你少来
You'll do nothing.
只有我  克里斯和李
The only people allowed anywhere near him are me,
可以靠近他
Chris and Lee, all right?
-我们轮班  -没问题
- We're doing shifts. - You got it, man.
什么都行  肯
Anything, Ken, all right.
你的角色是什么  巴克希医生
What's your role in this, Dr. Bakshi?
我的角色
My role?
我是斯潘德先生请来的
I was engaged by Mr. Spender
作为乐团的私人医生
as personal physician to the group.
那具体都做些什么
And what does that entail, exactly?
一群健康的小伙子
I wouldn't have thought a bunch of fit young men
应该不怎么需要一位私人医生
would have much need for a personal doctor.
你是想不到
Oh, you'd be surprised.
扭伤  神经衰弱
Sprains, nervous exhaustion...
巡演乐团必须保持最佳状态
A group on the road needs to be kept in tip-top condition.
你怎么做
How do you go about that?
靠药物吗
Pills, is it?
兴奋剂  安眠药
Uppers? Downers?
没有违法的东西
Nothing illegal.
但是的  偶尔开些安眠药
But yes, the occasional sleeping draught.
或兴奋类药物
The odd booster.
那他是服了什么
Right, so what's he taken here?
不是我给的东西
Nothing of mine.
我的诊断是  他被下了大剂量的
My diagnosis is he has been given a large dose
麦角酸酰二乙氨[LSD迷幻药]
of lysergic acid diethylamide.
他能恢复吗
And will he recover?
他的身体没问题
Oh, his body, yes.
但他的头脑
But his mind?
那真的要看剂量大小了
It really depends on the size of the dose.
斯潘德先生
Mr. Spender,
问几个问题
a few questions, please.
你是否知道
Have you any idea
尼克可能从哪得到的迷幻药
where Nick might have come by this LSD?
他们抽点大麻
They smoke a little pot,
好吗
all right?
或许还有致幻蘑菇  但没别的了
Mushrooms maybe, but that's it,
到此为止了
that's as far as it goes.
不会嗑什么厉害的
Nothing heavy.
巴克希医生说  他可能无法痊愈
Dr. Bakshi said he might not fully recover.
至少是他的神智
His wits, at any rate.
这对你希望乐团实现的收入目标会是个打击
It's gonna hit any revenue you were hoping to make from the group.
天啊  重要的不是钱
God, it's not about the money.
对我不是
Not for me.
是音乐
It been the music.
一直都是  从我认识他们就是这样
Always. From the second I saw them.
那乐团内的不和呢
What about infighting, within the group?
有人给他下药吗  不会的
Someone dosed him? No. No.
他们是有争吵  但他们是一家人
I mean they fight, sure, but they're family.
没人会伤害尼克的
Nobody would hurt Nick.
好  那乐团外部的人呢
Okay, then what about somebody outside the group?
那些女孩
One of the girls maybe?
不  大家都爱尼克
No, everybody loves Nicky.
克拉克太太说她听到有车
Mrs. Clark said she heard a car
在巴里·芬奇死的那晚的凌晨时分
pull up outside the house in the early hours,
停在了房子外面
on the day we found Barry Finch.
安娜-布丽特只是在搞事
Anna-Britt's just stirring.
她为什么要那么做
Why would she do that?
她认为我欠了尼克署名权
She thinks I did Chris out of some credit
是他们的一首歌
on one of the boys' songs,
《他爱你》  他们的第一首上榜曲
"He Loves You," Their first 45.
你有吗
Did you?
没有
No.
克里斯有天在
Chris was just playing around
彩排的时候乱拨弄弦
with chord changes in rehearsal, one day.
激发了尼克的灵感  第二天他就带着
It fired something up in Nicky, he comes in the next day
《他爱你》来了
with "He Loves You."
安娜-布丽特认为克里斯该有署名权
Anna-Britt thinks Chris needs credit for that.
但版权归属很明确
But copyright is very clear.
所以你那晚没从伦敦回来吗
So you didn't come back from London the other night?
我说了
I've told you.
我那晚在我芒特街的公寓
I was in my flat in Mount Street.
在跟美国那边通电话
On the phone to America.
那你不会介意我们
Well, then you'll have no objection
检查你的车了
to us examining your car?
为什么
What for?
请便
Help yourself.
我无可隐瞒
I've got nothing to hide.
好吧
Well...
我认为是完美匹配
I'd say that's a perfect match.
但光靠这个可不足以证明
Tough to make it stick on that alone.
牛津一半的车里都有十字扳手
Half the cars in Oxford must carry a wheel brace.
迷幻药能让他心脏停跳吗
Could LSD have stopped his heart?
是可能的
Well, it's possible.
过度刺激神经系统
Overstimulation of the nervous system?
罕见
Rare.
但有可能
But it could have done.
它有什么作用
What's it do?
会制造高强度的
It produces extreme visual
幻象和幻音
and auditory hallucinations.
化学上讲  一般无毒
Not usually toxic chemically,
但从行为上讲...
but behaviorally...?
怎么说
In what way?
丧失克制力
Loss of inhibition.
让人失去理智
Compromised rationality.
大部分与这种物质有关的死亡都是意外
Most deaths involving the substance are accidental.
走进车流中
Walking into traffic.
或是铁轨上
Onto railway lines.
从高楼坠下
Stepping off high buildings.
我去找实验室
I'll talk to the lab.
如果知道该找什么就好找了
Easier to find something if you know what you're looking for.
她好慈祥
She looks kind.
她是个慈祥的人吗
Is she kind?
是的
She was.
她过世了
She died.
失去爱的人好难受
It's hard losing someone you love.
我认为我爱爸爸远胜于我爱她
I think I loved Daddy much more than I love her.
我尽量去一样地爱她了  但是
I try to love her the same, but...
我很坏吧
I'm wicked, aren't I?
-不  -我觉得我坏
- No. - I think I am.
上帝看到一切
God sees all.
他清楚我心里有什么
He knows what's in my heart.
你觉得我会下地狱吗
Do you think I'm going to burn?
永远业火焚身
In hell forever and ever?
-不会的  -有时我希望她死了
- No. - Sometimes I wish she was dead.
我希望她死了  有人来带我
I wish she was dead and that someone would come
离开上帝
and take me away from God and...
所以  是的
So, yes.
可以说  我恨乔伊·佩蒂博
It would be fair to say I pretty much hate Joy Pettybon.
足以对此采取行动吗
Enough to do something about it?
我是采取行动了
I am doing something about it.
我用我仅有的钱
With what little money I do have,
跟着她的步伐走遍全国
I follow her around the country
尽我所能戳穿她的真面目
and do my best to denounce her for what she is.
那是什么
What's that?
伪君子
A hypocrite'.
她站在她的演讲台上
She stands on her soapbox
戴着巫婆帽  和赫达·霍普的眼镜
in that Harridan hat and those Hedda Hopper glasses--
一个转型娱乐记者的好莱坞女星
这女人显然是不了解什么叫着装打扮
I mean, the woman clearly wouldn't know couture from a dog turd--
她就站在那里
and she stands there,
那个比比划划的牧师  在旁怂恿她
with that pantomime horse of a vicar egging her on,
她满嘴的愤怒和仇恨
spouting bile and hatred...
她还好意思自称基督徒
and she has the brass neck to call herself a Christian?
你还做什么别的了吗
And what about doing anything else about it?
怎么说
In what way?
昨晚有人企图杀了她
Someone tried to kill her last night.
不
No.
不不不
No, no, no, no.
我支持的是抗议
I'm all for protest.
和平抗议
Peaceful protest.
她没事吧
Is she all right?
她是没事
She's all right, sir, yes.
但更多是因为走运
More by luck than anything else.
但格莱特利牧师今早被发现身亡
But the Reverend Golightly was found dead this morning.
似乎是被下毒了
It appears he's been poisoned.
你们不会以为
You can't think...
这跟我无关
It was nothing to do with me.
我对上帝发誓
I swear to God.
是啊  先生  现在对上帝发誓的不少呢
Yes, sir, there's a lot of that going about at the minute.
但我想请你去趟警局  给你宣读权利后
However, I think we might get a formal statement from you
做份正式口供
under caution down the station.
可以跟我们走一趟吗
If you'd like to come with us.
贝蒂娜  你来吗
Bettina, are you coming?
马上来  妈妈
In a minute, Mummy.
这个杰赛普  嫌疑大吗
Likely suspect, this Jessop character?
至少很可能  长官
Gotta be favorite, sir.
他非常仇视佩蒂博太太
He hates Mrs. Pettybon with a passion.
他们昨晚在全国直播电视节目上大吵
They clashed live on national television last night.
你的假设是
You're proceeding on the assumption
她才是真正的目标
she was the intended victim.
暂时是的  长官
Well, for now, sir, yes.
我们并无理由认为不是
We've no reason to think anything else.
我们对格莱特利牧师有何了解
What do we know about the Reverend Golightly?
没有家人  战前成为了牧师
Well, no family, ordained before the war,
在全国各地都任过职
ministered all over the country.
跟牛津有任何联系吗
Any connection with Oxford?
10年前曾短暂在圣玛丽任职
Brief spell as vicar of Saint Mary's, ten years ago.
圣玛丽
Saint Mary's.
巴里·芬奇曾是那里的唱诗班成员  直到变声
Barry Finch was a choirboy there, until his voice went.
看看芬奇尸体上的印记
Looking at the mark on Finch's body.
如果稍稍转动
If you were to rotate it,
可能是个十字架  是吧
it could be a cross, couldn't it?
两个杯子
Two glasses'.
拜托  妈妈
Please, Mummy.
什么都没发生
Nothing happened.
我们只是谈了会儿
We just talked.
你指望我相信吗
Do you expect me to believe that?
我清楚男人和女人
I know what goes on in bedrooms
在卧室里做什么
between men and women.
妈妈  求你  不要
Mummy, Mummy, please don't.
这是为了你好  贝蒂娜
It's for your own good, Bettina.
你一点也不善良
You're not kind'.
你好坏
You're wicked'.
不虔诚
And Godless'.
怪不得爸爸...
No wonder Daddy did...
牛津警局  有什么可以帮您的
Oxford Police Station, how may I help you?
喂
Hello? Hello?
请给我接警察局长
Would you put me through to the Chief Constable, please.
请问您是谁
Yes, who's calling, please?
我是佩蒂博太太  亲爱的
It's Mrs. Pettybon, dear.
清空你的一切思绪
Clear your mind of all things.
放下一切世间牵绊
Let go of all earthly attachments.
成为河里的一片叶子
Become a leaf on a river.
你在向下游漂流  漂向虚无
You are drifting downstream towards nothingness.
可能感觉像死亡
It may feel like death,
但那并非死去
but it is not dying.
进
Yes.
长官
Sir?
我刚跟警部通了电话
I've just got off the telephone from Division.
看来警察局长
It seems the Chief Constable
对佩蒂博太太的工作相当敬佩
is a great admirer of Mrs. Pettybon's work.
她有个女儿  叫贝蒂娜  是吧
She has a daughter. Bettina, is it?
是  长官
Yes, sir.
怯生生的小姑娘
Timid little thing.
是啊  佩蒂博太太认为
Yes, well, Mrs. Pettybon's of the impression
摩斯似乎跟她有不得体的
Morse may have overstepped the mark somewhat
行为
in that regard.
肯定是一派胡言  但警察局长
Nonsense, I'm sure, but the Chief Constable
要求他不要再参与
wants him removed from any further involvement
格莱特利案了
in the Golightly case.
对  她叫我进屋去开个窗
Yes, she asked me in to open the window.
窗卡住了
It had stuck.
所以你开了窗户就走了吗
So you just opened her window and went on your way.
怎么
What?
我们喝了一杯
Well, we had a drink.
在酒吧吗
In the bar?
她有瓶酒
She had a bottle.
我在那里待了半小时
I was there for half an hour,
至多45分钟
45 minutes most.
你在执勤  你根本不该逗留
You were on duty-- you shouldn't have been there at all.
这下你被批评了
Now you've been handed the black spot,
还是从最上头来的批评
straight from the top'.
你觉得这让我多难堪
Where d'you think that leaves me?
布莱特先生要你撤出格莱特利案
Mr. Bright wants you off the Golightly case.
你最好把你的脑瓜
Well, you'd better turn that brain of yours
拿去破巴里·芬奇的案子
back onto Barry Finch.
查出结果来  布莱特先生就又会赞赏你了
Get a result, you'll be back into Mr. Bright's good books.
他心里是为你好的
He does have your best interests at heart.
那他真会掩饰
Hides it well.
那是因为他比你以为的
That's because he's a lot smarter
要聪明多了
than you give him credit for.
你别抽了吧
Why don't you lay off that?
稍稍保持会儿头脑清醒
Keep a clear head for a bit?
一切都会没事的
Look. It's all gonna be all right.
是吗
Is it?
你是我弟弟
You're my little brother.
我绝不会允许你出事的
I'd never let anything happen to you.
怎么  也开始赶时髦了
What's this? Are you joining the in crowd?
我觉得我对野林乐团已经无所不知了
I think I know all I need to know about the Wildwood.
听听
Listen to this.
"有时  克里斯托弗会创作一段贝斯乐段
"Sometimes Christopher will come up with a bass riff
激起我的灵感
"That really fires me up.
大家都会为音乐出力
"We all contribute to the arrangements,
但克里斯托弗有时会想出
"But Christopher sometimes has an idea
能让一首歌脱胎换骨的点子"
that totally transforms a song."
话都说不好
Drivel.
他们也不会那么糟吧
Well, they can't be that awful.
他们把尼克的歌词跟詹姆斯·乔伊斯
They're comparing Nick's lyrics
和奥斯卡·王尔德这种名作家比呢
to James Joyce and Oscar Wilde.
谁啊
Who are?
评论家
The critics.
据说有很多象征和隐喻
They're full of symbolism and allusion apparently.
-是有很多什么东西  -我好像读到
- Full of something. - Didn't I read somewhere
他们差点给自己起名
that they nearly called themselves
-毒蘑菇  -没错
- The Toadstools? - That's right.
纪念尼克和克里斯托弗以前服的致幻蘑菇
In honor of the mushrooming trips Nick and Christopher used to go on.
如果起初是尼克和克里斯托弗的乐队
If it was Nick and Christopher's band originally,
那个哥哥是个什么地位
then where did the other brother fit in?
肯是更好的吉他手
Ken was the better guitarist.
似乎是自己挤进去  夺过了控制权
Seems to have muscled his way in and taken control.
克里斯托弗成了备胎
Christopher's become a bit of a spare wheel.
但这就是娱乐圈嘛
But that's show business.
车坏了
Car trouble?
不是
Not quite.
不是十字架吗
Not a cross then?
你怎么想到的
Where'd you get that idea?
楚拉夫的一句话
Something Trewlove said.
他可能是被用车移尸吧
He could have been moved by car, couldn't he?
趴着放
Laid face down.
那就可能是十字扳手留下的印记了
The wheel brace could have caused that mark, then.
格莱特利牧师的主要死因
The primary cause of Reverend Golightly's death
是大出血导致心脏衰竭
was hemorrhage leading to heart failure.
自然死亡吗
Natural causes?
我没那么说吧
I don't think I said that, did I?
那是什么导致的
So what caused it?
泻药
Laxative.
格莱特利牧师的肾基本完了
The Reverend Golightly's kidneys were all but shot.
泻药中的镁导致了低镁症
Magnesium in the laxative caused hypomagnesemia,
呼吸急促  低血压  心律失常
respiratory distress, low blood pressure, arrhythmia...
所以才会吐血  是吧
That would explain the blood, would it?
所以才会呕吐
It would explain the vomiting.
但是
However,
他还患有
he was also suffering
未被发现的主动脉瘤
from an undiagnosed aortic aneurysm.
其他症状让他的身体系统不堪重负
The rest of it put such a strain on his system
主动脉瘤就破裂了
that it ruptured.
因此才会出血
Hence the blood.
把内脏吐出来了
Puked his guts up, then.
毫不夸张
Literally.
你当年一定是个诗意的孩子  警长
What a lyrical child you must have been, Sergeant?
但本不该致命的
It shouldn't have been fatal, though.
一般不会
Not ordinarily, no.
至少对身体健康的人并不致命
Certainly not to anyone in decent health.
上帝饶恕我
God forgive me.
你好  客房服务
Hello, chambermaid?
有人吗
Hello?
先生
Sir?
格莱特利有进展吗
Progress on Golightly?
佩蒂博太太虽然
Mrs. Pettybon may have sent
给自己寄了威胁信
the threatening letter to herself,
但我们仍偏向于认为是杂志主编
but our favorite for dosing the chocolates
给巧克力下了毒  长官
is still this magazine editor, sir.
是啊  总体上有好多恨意
Yes, well, a lot of hate about altogether.
比以前多了  是不是
More than there used to be, d'you think?
我可说不好  长官
Oh, I wouldn't know, sir.
是因为电视吗
Television, perhaps?
佩蒂博太太是这么想的
That would certainly be Mrs. Pettybon's angle.
两次世界大战
Two world wars.
死了数百万人
Millions dead.
那些暴行
Atrocities?
集中营  原子弹
The camps? The Bomb?
她要怎么把那归咎于电视
She'd be hard put to lay that at the door of television.
恨一直存在  长官
Always been hate, sir.
能追溯到该隐和亚伯
Right back to Cain and Abel.
这也好吧
Just as well, I suppose.
死了大概六小时了
Dead about six hours.
那么是凌晨3点
So 3:00 in the night?
差不多
Around then.
死因呢
Cause?
我得先检查一下才能知道
I shan't know until I've had a grub about.
但他显然是吃坏了什么
But something disagreed with him, plainly.
呕吐物里有尚未消化的巧克力
Half-digested chocolates amongst the ejecta.
那是哪来的
Where've they come from?
她昨晚收到了好多盒
She received boxes of them last night.
佩蒂博太太
Mrs. Pettybon.
在《年鉴》节目之后
After the Almanac show.
巧克力  鲜花  祝福者送的
Chocolates, flowers, from well-wishers.
据说她到哪都会如此
Happens wherever she goes, apparently.
会不会是有人下药了
Could someone have laced them with something, do you think?
有可能
Yes, perhaps...
-医生  -先生们
- Doctor. - Gentlemen.
没比往常严重
No more than usual.
格莱特利牧师的事有消息了吗
Any news about Reverend Golightly?
我恐怕已被撤出了案子
I've been taken off the case, I'm afraid.
因为我
Because of me.
不是
No.
是因为我
Because of me.
这是你吗
Is this you?
小时候
It was. Once.
你妈妈
Your mother.
如果检测出来  那就三个了
If it does come back positive, that makes it three.
巴里·芬奇  格莱特利牧师  尼克·威尔丁
Barry Finch, Reverend Golightly and now Nick Wilding.
都算是被下毒了  至少是涉及到毒品
All poisoned, one way or another, drugs leastways.
但尼克·威尔丁没死
Except Nick Wilding's not dead.
那可能多是因为走运  而非判断力
More by luck than judgment maybe.
或许吧  或许那只是为了封他的口
Maybe, or perhaps it was just an attempt to shut him up.
为了什么事
About what?
巴里·芬奇
Barry Finch.
你本该保护我们
You were meant to keep us safe.
威胁是针对你的
The threat was made against you.
据我所知  你还在呢
So far as I can see, you're still here.
我真不知道你为什么要来
I really don't know why you've come by.
我说了我不打算起诉了
I said I didn't want to press charges.
我们不是来谈你挨打的事  杰赛普先生
We're not here to talk about your beating, Mr. Jessop.
我们是为佩蒂博太太而来
We're here to talk about Mrs. Pettybon.
她害你的杂志社被关
She got your magazine closed down.
《精彩时代》  是吧
Exciting Times, isn't that right?
她还害我留了犯罪案底
She also landed me with a criminal record
蹲了监狱
and a prison sentence.
还顺带害我破产
Oh, and brought me to bankruptcy into the bargain.
你应该不怎么喜欢佩蒂博太太咯
I imagine you don't much care for Mrs. Pettybon?
我现在靠施舍
I'm living on handouts
和一小笔我父母给的零用钱度日
and a small allowance from my parents.
他们给我钱  是因为我答应
They give me money on the understanding
再不会给他们蒙羞
I never darken their door again.
我找不到工作
I can't get a job, I'm...
芬奇参与了群交吗
So Finch was part of some sort of orgy?
有些人喜欢
All right for some.
可我连音乐抢椅子都抢不上
I could never get a seat at musical chairs,
更别说别的了
never mind anything else.
你不会喜欢的  警长  就你那后背
You wouldn't like it, Sergeant, not with your back.
是巴里·芬奇的表
It's Barry Finch's watch.
看来她是雨露均沾啊  这个皮帕
She was spreading her favors then, this Pippa girl?
你在哪找到的
Where did you find it?
一个空土耳其软糖盒里
In an empty Turkish Delight box
放在尼克·威尔丁的小窝里
Nick Wilding kept in his den.
或许他是留着自己欣赏
Maybe he kept it for his own entertainment.
会不会是勒索
It could be blackmail, couldn't it?
这如果登上周日报纸
It wouldn't do much for their image
他们的形象肯定要受损
if this got into the Sunday papers.
如今的流行明星不都这样吗  长官
Almost expected of pop stars these days, sir?
也没几个会这样吧  长官
I don't know so much, sir.
行了  警员
All right, Constable.
不  说吧
No, no, go on,
楚拉夫警员
Constable Trewlove.
长官  公众意见很善变
Well, sir, the public can be pretty fickle.
这样的丑闻可能让他们彻底完蛋
Something like this could bring the whole house of cards down.
不
No.
至少斯潘德为他们投资了那么多
Well, Spender has too much investment in those lads
不会允许那种事发生
to let that happen.
更重要的是  是谁拍的照片  为什么
The bigger point is, who took the picture and why?
继续查
Keep at it.
我有一两件事想问问佩蒂博太太
There's one or two things I want to put to Mrs. Pettybon.
怎么回事
What's this?
格莱特利案  长官  斯特兰奇
The Golightly case, sir. Strange?
我查了查佩蒂博太太  长官
I've had a dig into Mrs. Pettybon, sir.
她是没什么  但发现了她丈夫的案底
Nothing for her, but we've got a match on her husband.
他不是死了吗
He's dead, isn't he?
自杀
Suicide.
女儿做完周日晚祷回来
Daughter got back from Sunday evensong
发现他用腰带吊死在了栏杆上
to find him hanging by his belt from the bannister.
原来他周五晚因严重猥亵罪被抓
Turns out he'd been pinched for gross indecency on the Friday evening
周一本要上庭的
and was looking at court on the Monday.
你现在一定
Well, I suppose you must be
非常得意吧
feeling very pleased with yourself.
并不
Not particularly.
但这解释了你为何如此仇恨
But it certainly explains your vicious hatred
达德利·杰赛普这种人
of men like Dudley Jessop.
我爱我丈夫
I loved my husband.
我以为他是的那个人
The man I thought he was.
失去他  让我无比震惊
To lose him, it was a terrible shock.
但得知他有那样的癖好...
But to find out that he'd been carrying on like that...
是你逼他选了那条路
You drove him to it.
我听到你说的话了
I heard you.
他活该
It was what he deserved.
那总比让全家蒙羞好
Better that than bringing shame on the family.
你个贱人
You bitch'.
你真是个贱人
You utter bitch'.
好了
All right, all right.
All right.
我要走了
I'm leaving.
你下地狱去吧
You can rot in hell for all I care.
她会回来的
She'll be back.
不
No.
她不会的
She won't.
你觉得是怎么回事
What do you think happened?
我觉得巴里·芬奇死在了枫芯堂
I think Barry Finch died at Maplewick Hall
拉弗·斯潘德回来  收拾了残局
and Ralph Spender came back and tidied up,
他们把芬奇的尸体搬去了酒馆院子
then moved Finch's body to the pub yard.
那你怎么还不逮捕他
So why haven't you arrested him?
因为到目前  他有不在场证明
Because so far his alibi stands up.
他在伦敦跟美国那边通话
That he was in London on the phone to the United States,
策划跟谁巡演...
planning a tour with the, uh...
奇想乐团吗
Kinks?
奇想乐团吗  不可能
The Kinks? He can't have.
为什么
Why not?
奇想乐团被美国禁了
The Kinks are banned from America.
工作许可的什么问题
It's something to do with work permits.
真的吗
Really?
如果有人找我  我在枫芯堂
I'll be out at Maplewick Hall if anyone wants me.
你好
Hello.
我找斯潘德先生
I'm looking for Mr. Spender.
他不在
Um... he's not here.
男生们带尼克去看专家了
The boys have taken Nick to see a specialist.
在萨里郡什么地方
Somewhere in Surrey.
拉弗少校和布鲁诺带他们去了
Major Ralph and Bruno have taken them.
皮帕也去了
Pippa's gone, too.
你想喝一杯吗
Do you want a drink?
好  谢谢
Yes, please.
那克里斯托弗的妻子呢
What about Christopher's wife?
安娜-布丽特吗
Anna-Britt?
他们好像送她和孩子去克里斯妈妈家了
I think they were dropping her off at Chris's mother's with the baby.
在城里
It's in town somewhere.
你被看到了  杰赛普先生
You were seen, Mr. Jessop.
在《年鉴》节目后台转悠
Mooching around backstage at the Almanac show.
你有充足机会
You had the perfect opportunity
留下毒巧克力
to leave those poisoned chocolates.
谁说的
Who told you that?
那姑娘吗
The girl, I presume?
什么姑娘
What girl?
安娜-布丽特和尼克的关系如何
How were things between Anna-Britt and Nick?
什么意思
How do you mean?
尼克和克里斯是好朋友  是吧
Well, Nick and Chris were good friends, weren't they?
他们是同学
They went to school together.
我就想知道是否存在任何嫉妒...
I just wondered if there was any jealousy or...
我说不好
I couldn't say.
为什么这么问
Why?
就是好奇
Just curious.
她化妆间里有个年轻女人
There was a young woman in her dressing room.
她说她是佩蒂博太太的助理
She said she was Mrs. Pettybon's assistant.
她还问我为什么进去
She asked me what I was doing there.
我说我迷路了  然后就走了
I said I was lost, and went on my way.
她女儿吗  贝蒂娜
The daughter, you mean. Bettina?
不是
No. No.
我知道她的样子
I know what she looks like.
小可怜
Poor creature.
这个女孩  你能描述她吗
This girl, can you describe her?
我可以去尼克房间看看吗
Would you mind if I looked in Nick's room?
当然
Sure.
毒巧克力是给佩蒂博太太的
The poisoned chocolates were meant for Mrs. Pettybon, all right.
她威胁要禁止乐团的唱片在直播电视上播出
She threatened to have the group's record banned live on television.
会是拉弗·斯潘德指使她的吗
Could Ralph Spender have put her up to it?
那种事不利于乐团的销售量吧
Something like that could have damaged the group's sales, couldn't it?
我觉得他也不会做得那么过分
I don't think even he'd go that far.
他只会试图收买她
He'd have tried to buy her off.
不  这就是仇恨
No, this is good old-fashioned hate.
纯粹简单
Pure and simple.
摩斯呢
Where's Morse?
你在找什么
What is it you're looking for?
我能帮忙吗
Can I help?
皮帕在跟尼克上床
Pippa was sleeping with Nick.
是吗
Is that right?
是
Yes.
分分合合吧
On and off.
还有巴里·芬奇
And Barry Finch.
他怎么了
What about him?
她也跟他上床了吗
Was she sleeping with him too?
我得去接一下
I'd better get that.
枫芯堂
Maplewick Hall.
我是瑟斯戴督察
This is Detective Inspector Thursday.
牛津市警局
Oxford City Police.
你是谁
Who am I speaking to?
喂
Hello?
有位摩斯警员应该在你那里
I believe you have Detective Constable Morse with you.
我想马上跟他说话
I'd like to speak to him now, please.
喂
Hello?
你喜欢摄影
You're a keen photographer?
我的爱好
It's my thing.
拉弗说我们可能出本书
Ralph says we might do a book,
乐队的照片集
pictures of the band.
这是你拍的吗
So did you take this?
是尼克  皮帕和巴里·芬奇  是吧
That's Nick, Pippa and Barry Finch, isn't it?
他们知道你拍了吗
Did they know you'd taken it?
我猜他们不知道  他们睡着了
No, I don't suppose they did, they're asleep.
-是尼克叫我拍的  -我觉得不是
- Nick asked me to. - I don't think so.
不
No.
我觉得这是隐私
I think this was private.
除了涉事人  应该没人知道
I doubt anyone knew, except those involved,
当然了  你也知道
and you, of course.
但你没受邀
Only you weren't invited.
知道什么
Anyone knew what?
尼克跟皮帕和巴里都上床了
That Nick was sleeping with Pippa and Barry.
他们新专辑的标题就是
It's there in the title of their new album.
《男孩女孩出来玩》
"Boys and Girls Come Out to Play."
男孩和女孩
Boys and girls.
他们唱片的沟槽上还有句话
There's also a message on the groove of the LP.
YEMKTTHL4099
Y.E.M.K.T.T.H.L. 4099.
那只是母带号
That's just a matrix number.
"但每个人都杀死自己所爱"[王尔德]
"Yet each man kills the thing he loves."
4099.
是奥斯卡·王尔德在瑞丁监狱时的
The prisoner number assigned to Oscar Wilde
因同性恋相关罪名入狱
牢房号
when he was sent to Reading Jail.
我觉得你无法忍受
I think you couldn't stand
尼克跟巴里·芬奇上床了
that Nick was sleeping with Barry Finch,
所以你等到他昏睡过去
so you waited until he passed out,
便勒死了他
and then you strangled him.
尼克醒来时
Nick must have come to,
还没从毒品和酒精的作用下清醒过来
his mind still clouded by drink and drugs,
看到巴里死在了他身边
found Barry dead beside him.
他无法确定不是他的性爱游戏出了错
He couldn't be sure that his sex game hadn't gone wrong.
-什么性爱游戏  -在萨德的《贾丝汀》里
- What "Sex game"? - In Justine de Sade's book--
有一个角色
one of the characters
让另一个人吊着他  直至他不省人事
has another hang him to the point of unconsciousness.
我觉得尼克也尝试过这个点子
I think Nick experimented with the same idea.
问题是
The thing is,
你那晚其实只需要等
all you had to do that night, really, was wait.
什么
What?
你去勒巴里·芬奇的时候
By the time you strangled Barry Finch,
他已经要死了
he was already dying.
他对他服的毒品产生了不良反应
He'd had a bad reaction to the drugs he'd taken.
但那还不够  是吧
But that wasn't it, was it?
你本以为  除掉了巴里
You thought with Barry out of the way,
尼克有天就会爱上你  但那是不可能的
Nick might one day be yours, but he never would have been.
所以你才给他下了迷幻药
That's why you slipped him the LSD.
我为什么要伤害尼克
Why would I hurt Nick?
我爱他
I love him'.
他也爱我
He loves me.
我知道他爱我
I know he does.
老天爷  他为我写了《詹妮弗有时》
For God's sake, he wrote "Jennifer Sometimes" for me'.
不是的  那不是讲你的
No, he didn't. That's not about you.
-就是  他说了  -不是的
- It is'. He told me. - No, it's not.
"回到旧学校
"Go back to the old school.
看一颗毒蘑菇下面"
Look under the toadstool."
歌词跟你对不上
The lyrics don't apply to you.
但跟克里斯托弗·克拉克对得上
But they do apply to Christopher Clark.
是《克里斯托弗有时》
It's "Christopher Sometimes."
但他总不能在电台上唱这个
But he could hardly put that on the radio.
但...
But...
那是我的名字
...it's my name.
如果不是写给我的
If it wasn't for me,
他又为什么要写詹妮弗
why would he call it Jennifer?
为了韵律
To make scansion.
克里斯托弗
Christopher,
詹妮弗
Jennifer,
音节一样多
same amount of syllable...
出什么问题了吗
Something wrong?
没事的
It's all right.
你不用怕什么
You have nothing to be afraid of.
除非你有恐惧
Unless you have.
你脑子里有什么  就会看到什么
What you take in with you is what you find in there.
你一定看到过很恐怖的景象
You must have seen some terrible things.
那都在等待你
It's all waiting for you.
你能看到什么  摩斯
What's in there, Morse?
-放开我  -摩斯
- Get off me'. - Morse'.
摩斯
Morse'.
好了
All right. All right.
-放开我  -你给他下什么了
- Get off me. - What've you given him?
你给他下什么了
What've you given him?'
没事了  摩斯
All right, Morse.
没事
All right.
他能恢复吗
Will he recover?
得等等看了  长官
Time will tell, sir.
但他经历了地狱
But he's been to hell and back.
只能希望她给他下的不是迷幻药
The only hope is it wasn't LSD she gave him.
她把仅剩的都用在尼克·威尔丁身上了
She used the last of that on Nick Wilding.
他的情况可不妙
And there doesn't look to be much hope for him.
她给摩斯用了什么
So what did she use on Morse?
混合物  天仙子  曼德拉草
A concoction of henbane, mandrake
蔓陀罗
and jimsonweed...
效果类似迷幻药
Effects are not dissimilar to LSD.
也是她给佩蒂博太太寄了巧克力吗
And it was she who sent the chocolates to Mrs. Pettybon?
是  长官
Yes, sir.
她想报复她
She wanted to get back at her for
企图让乐团的专辑被禁
trying to get the group's record banned.
结果被格莱特利牧师吃了
Only they ended up with Reverend Golightly.
这姑娘太可怕了
Girl sounds an absolute hellion.
摩斯
Morse.
今天周几
What day is it?
咸牛肉
Corned beef.
是周五
It's Friday.
没错
That's right.
周五
Friday.
她招了吗
Did she confess?
艾玛
Um... Emma.
嗯
Oh, yeah.
是她把照片放在了土耳其软糖盒里
She planted the photos in the Turkish Delight box
她给尼克下药  是想毁掉他的名声
after she'd doped Nick to discredit him.
好吧
Well.
我不打扰你休息了
I'd better let you get some rest.
不急着回来
No need to rush back.
你慢慢来
In your own good time.
摩斯
Morse.
牛津2947
Oxford 2947.
我是接线员
This is the operator.
这里有一通利明顿的对方付费电话
I have a reverse charge call from Leamington.
你是否接受费用
Will you accept the charges?
我在利明顿好像不认识谁
I don't think I know anyone in Leamington.
对对
Oh, yes.
接受
Yes.
正在为您接通
Connecting you now.
请讲  来电人
Go ahead, caller.
喂
Hello?
瑟斯戴小姐
Miss Thursday?
对不起  先生  她挂断了
I'm sorry, sir, she's disconnected.